<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R Package on Network Science</title>
    <link>/tags/r-package/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R Package on Network Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>M.Smith@greenwich.ac.uk (Matthew Smith)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>M.Smith@greenwich.ac.uk (Matthew Smith)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r-package/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ITNr Version 0.2.0</title>
      <link>/post/itnr-version-0-2-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>M.Smith@greenwich.ac.uk (Matthew Smith)</author>
      <guid>/post/itnr-version-0-2-0/</guid>
      <description>International Trade Network (ITN) Analysis in RA new version of my package ITNr (0.2.0) is now on CRAN!
The ITNr package presents a set of functions of to clean trade data, implement desciptitve analysis of the ITN and create a range of plots.
I have updated and corrected the documentation for function is the last version, and have added several new functions. These include:
core_periphery_weighted: To identify whether nodes belong to the core/periphery in weighted directed/undirected networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating R packages, R markdown and blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/creating-r-packages-using-r-markdown-and-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>M.Smith@greenwich.ac.uk (Matthew Smith)</author>
      <guid>/post/creating-r-packages-using-r-markdown-and-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>As this my very first blog post for this site (created using blogdown) I decided to write some comments/general points on my experience moving from a being a general R user making use of functions to writing R packages, using GitHub, and making use of markdown and blogdown.
PackagesThroughout my PhD I had to create networks from international trade data. This involved cleaning the data, removing unnecessary actors (such as territories like “Other Asia not elsewhere classified”), applying a threshold, so the network only contained ties that were some percentage of world trade and finally convert this into a network file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>