<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blogdown on Network Science</title>
    <link>/tags/blogdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blogdown on Network Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>M.Smith3@napier.ac.uk (Matthew Smith)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>M.Smith3@napier.ac.uk (Matthew Smith)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/blogdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Note on deploying with Netlify</title>
      <link>/post/2023-08-04-note-on-deploying-with-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>M.Smith3@napier.ac.uk (Matthew Smith)</author>
      <guid>/post/2023-08-04-note-on-deploying-with-netlify/</guid>
      <description>This is a post for anyone coming back to update their website after some time and encountering issues. In a previous post I describe how I created the site using blogdown.
One issue I encountered when updating my website then using blogdown::serve_site() to view it, was the that the blog posts no longer appeared on the main page. After some searching the solution was to simply update Hugo using blogdown::install_hugo(). Then to adjust the Hugo versions listed in the config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating R packages, R markdown and blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/creating-r-packages-using-r-markdown-and-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>M.Smith3@napier.ac.uk (Matthew Smith)</author>
      <guid>/post/creating-r-packages-using-r-markdown-and-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>As this my very first blog post for this site (created using blogdown) I decided to write some comments/general points on my experience moving from a being a general R user making use of functions to writing R packages, using GitHub, and making use of markdown and blogdown.
Packages Throughout my PhD I had to create networks from international trade data. This involved cleaning the data, removing unnecessary actors (such as territories like “Other Asia not elsewhere classified”), applying a threshold, so the network only contained ties that were some percentage of world trade and finally convert this into a network file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
